JACOB GRANBERRY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER
AUSTIN TEXAS

CONTACT

940-782-3440

JACOBGRANBERRY@GMAIL.COM

GITHUB.COM/JACOBGRANBERRY

LINKEDIN.COM/IN/JACOB-GRANBERRY

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JAVASCRIPT/ES6
- REACT/REDUX
- GIT
- REST API
- NODEJS
- EXPRESS
- ANGULARJS
- HTML/CSS
- SCSS
- AXIOS
- MYSQL
- MONGODB
- SOCKET.IO
- AWS
- CHAI/MOCHA
- JEST/ENZYME
- WEBPACK
- JQUERY
- PHOTOSHOP

EDUCATION

HACK REACTOR 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE

BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS, SCULPTURE 2007 - 2011

MIDWESTERN STATE UNIVERSITY

PROFILE

I have a background in art and believe it formed the foundation from which I have built strong engineering skills, and also effectively closes the gap that sometimes exists between designers and engineers.

I also founded a popular fan project called WesterosCraft, a Minecraft server building the world of Game of Thrones. It has been in numerous publications, holds a Guinness World Record, exhibited in museums, and continues to impress and innovate in the community-driven video game space.

APPLICATIONS

GOAL SQUAD

FRONT END ENGINEER | GOALSQUADGAME.COM

A PROGRESSIVE WEB APP THAT LETS USERS SET GOALS AND GET REWARDED WITH DIFFERENT CREATURES TO GAME WITH.

- Designed and implemented a responsive front-end using Semantic UI and custom styling
- Implemented speed optimizations using compression and caching
- Used AWS to deploy using an RDS database and Ubuntu server
- Created feature using MySQL and Express to let users toggle creatures and persistently save their position on a page

HACKXCHANGE

FULL STACK ENGINEER | HACKXCHANGE.HEROKUAPP.COM

A FORUM FOR CODE REVIEW AND TROUBLESHOOTING WITH AN IN-APP CURRENCY USED TO JUDGE QUALITY OF POSTS.

- Implemented front-end filtering and asynchronous framework to gift in-app currency
- Created a random chance mechanism to spend and award in-app currency based on results
- Designed ability to toggle between day and night themes based on preference
- Used an existing jQuery library, highlight.js, to add syntax highlighting to posts

WESTEROSCRAFT

FULL STACK ENGINEER/FOUNDER | WESTEROSCRAFT.COM

A MINECRAFT SERVER AND COMMUNITY BUILDING THE WORLD OF GAME OF THRONES

- Founded the project and grew from dozens to over 30 thousand community members and a YouTube channel with over 2 million views
- Assign duties, responsibilities, and spans of authority to project staff
- Responsible for front-end development
- Template integration using the Xenforo CMS

GRASSROOTS

FULL STACK ENGINEER | HR-GRASSROOTS.HEROKUAPP.COM

A SOCIAL MEDIA SITE THAT CONNECTS VOTERS WITH CANDIDATES RUNNING IN LOCAL AND NATIONAL ELECTIONS.

- Designed and built frontend look using Semantic UI, focusing on data presentation and user experience
- Built a robust signup form that has several input fields based on conditionals and custom alerts

EXPERIENCE

FRANK & VICTOR

JUNE 2018 - OCT 2018

FRONTEND DEVELOPER - CONTRACT

- Take static designs and understand how that would translate to code using HTML/CSS and Javascript
- Take that translation, and write the code (Markup, Styling, Scripting, Integration, Deployment)
- Work with other developers in a rapid team environment

HORIZON BANK

2012 - 2018

IT HELPDESK MANAGER

- · Promoted to IT Helpdesk Manager from cash operations position after two years
- Answered user questions regarding computer software and hardware operation to resolve problems
- Set up equipment for employee use, performing or ensuring proper installation of cables, operating systems, and appropriate software